HR INTERN

Summary

An enthusiastic student, highly motivated and committed to developing personally and professionally. Have the ability to learn quickly, work efficiently and use my educational knowledge effectively in work settings. Skilled in research, multi-tasking, time management and communication. Experienced in human resource / organisational management, counselling and business development.Â

Educational Background

Master of Arts, Organisational Psychology 2018 Alliant International University i1/4 City, State, United States California School of Professional Psychology

Master of Science , Counselling Psychology 2015 Avinashilingam Institute for Home Science and Higher Education for Women $i^{1}/4$ City , State , India GPA - $\textbf{3.63}\hat{\textbf{A}}$

Bachelor of Arts, Mass Communication 2013 Amrita Viswa Vidhyapeetham i¹/₄ City, State, India

Amrita School of Communication

GPA - 3.07Â

Experience

HR Intern Jul 2016 to Current

Air Transport International i1/4 Kansas City, MO

I get candidates moved through the hiring process, making sure that they are properly credentialed and meet all of the company's and the clients requirements. \hat{A} \hat{A}

- Basic background checks Â Â Â Â Â Â Â Â Â Â Â
- Contact candidate's references & collect necessary information
- License and employment verification -Reviewing/uploading credentialsÂ
- Pre-screen applicants from job boards (Indeed & Zip Recruiter)
- Make and send badges
- Attend/transfer calls, take messages
- Work independently and as part of a team to achieve the company's goals.

Bookstore Volunteer Feb 2016 to Jul 2016

Olsson Associates il San Diego, CA

- Opening the store
- Account and check the closing and opening balance
- Maintain complete and accurate records of the store's transactions
- Rearrange books to maintain a neat and tidy reading area
- Assessed customer needs and responded to questions

Assistant to the General Manager Apr 2015 to Nov 2015

Stonex Group Inc. i1/4 Orlando, FL

- Managed the day-to-day tactical and long-term strategic activities within the business.
- Reviewed and approved billing invoices and expense reports.
- Counselled and mentored 53 staff members by offering constructive feedback, stress management techniques and guidance.
- Traveled with the manager to take notes and prepare minutes at meetings.
- Screened telephone calls and inquiries and directed them as appropriate.
- Maintained and recorded financial accounts of daily sales, purchases and other expenses.Â

Student Intern Jan 2015 to Feb 2015

Lockheed Martin i1/4 Tacoma, WA

- Administrative Assistance.
- Conducted & scored tests (16PF, Stress Inventories) to new clients and as follow-ups.
- Established rapport, collected & organised new client data.
- Administered "Positive Therapy" to patients.
- Assisted with rehabilitation activities.
- Individual, Family & Matrimonial Well Being/Therapy, Educational counselling, De- addiction / Smoking cessation and suicide prevention.Â

Intern Dec 2014 to Jan 2015

Manoshanti Family Counselling Centre i1/4 City, STATE

- Assistance and guidance to families below poverty line.
- Counselling individuals with issues relating to family, marital, legal issues.
- Provided sex education, awareness about good/bad touch to young school students.
- Observed the counselling sessions provided to sex workers.Â

Athma Institute For Mental Health & Social Sciences il/4 City, STATE

- The internship program was systematically split to accommodate sufficient training in De-addiction centre, Special school for mentally challenged children, Psychiatric clinic for adults and counselling centre.
- Witnessed and assisted with an ECT session administered by the Chief Doctors.
- · Collected information about clients, using techniques such as testing, interviewing, discussion, and observation.
- Gathered feedback from patients on medications, diagnosis and effectiveness of therapies.
- Gained knowledge and experience observing doctors provide counselling to patients and families.Â

Skills

- Microsoft Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint, Word.Â
- Excellent communication Skills
- Organisational Skills
- SPSS
- Data Entry

Researches

Autosuggestion as a mediator in weight management in female college students. Master's Thesis. (M.Sc, 2014-15)Â

- Sample: 82 female college students, convenient sampling method. The selection of the 82 participants were based on the Inclusion and Exclusion Criteria.
- The participants selected were assessed for their anthropometric data and they also completed WHO (Five) Well- Being Index. Group A (Exercise Diet Autosuggestion) and Group B (Exercise Diet).
- Results: A marginal but not a statistically significant difference in the body weight of the participants in both Group A and Group B. There was a statistically significant difference in the well-being of the participants in both Group A and Group B.Â

Mindfulness and Burnout of Teachers in StateBoard and Matriculation schools (Demographic factors). Master's Project. (M.Sc, 2014)

- Sample: 150 (51 Female and 24 Male in State board)(58 Female and 17 Male in matriculation)
- Scales: Mindfulness Attention Awareness scale and Burnout Inventory.
- The data were analysed by standard statistical tools such as karl pearson co-efficient of correlation, analysis of variance and t-test.
- Result: There were no statistically significant relationship between Mindfulness and Burnout in both Matriculation and State board schools.Â

Relation between Indian Zodiac and Personality types (MBTI). Master's Project. (M.Sc, 2015)

- Sample: 100 samples (Female 52 & Male 48), were randomly selected.
- The Myers Briggs Type Indicator (MBTI) was administered and scored.
- The results showed that there was no significant relation between the two variables.
- The sample size cannot determine the relationship, further studies can be done to conclude or disprove the findings of the current study.Â

Publications

- Snega Prabha S. A writer in the Mind. SPEAR (Sawyerpuram Pope's Emerging Aspirants In Research). Volume: II, No: 2. ISSN:2319-1902. July-December 2013.
- Dr. Preetha Menon, Snega Prabha S. Autosuggestion as a Mediator in Weight Management in Female College Students.
 International Journal of Scientific Research, Vol. 4, Issue: 7 July 2015.Â

Certifications

- Foundation Course on Education of Children with Learning Disabilities, Certified by Rehabilitation Council of India. (2014)
- TA-101. Introduction to Transactional Analysis. (2015)
- Hypnotism and it's Application in practice. (2015)
- Bio Ethics in Research. (2014)Â

Affiliations

APA - American Psychological Association (2016)

• AffiliateÂ

Volunteer Activities

- San Diego Humane Society San Diego, CA (June 2016 Present)
- Humane Animal Society India (Aug 2014 Nov 2015)
- **Puppy Palace** India (Aug 2014 Nov 2015)